<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>SOFADashboard on SOFAStack</title><link>/en/projects/sofa-dashboard/</link><description>Recent content in SOFADashboard on SOFAStack</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>zh-CN</language><atom:link href="/en/projects/sofa-dashboard/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Copyright statement</title><link>/en/projects/sofa-dashboard/notice/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/en/projects/sofa-dashboard/notice/</guid><description>Copyright statement of dependent components SOFADashboard uses some third-party open-source components, including but not limited to:
Spring under Apache 2.0 license Spring Boot under Apache 2.0 license SLF4j under the MIT License SOFABolt under Apache License 2.0 SOFABolt under Apache License 2.0 Curator under Apache License 2.0</description></item><item><title>Dashboard client</title><link>/en/projects/sofa-dashboard/dashboard-client/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/en/projects/sofa-dashboard/dashboard-client/</guid><description>You can view basic information of your application on SOFADashboard, including the IP address, ports, and health check status. This feature is dependent on the SOFADashboard client. If you want to display the information about an application on the SOFADashboard control page, import the sofa-dashboard-client dependency.
&amp;lt;denpendency&amp;gt; &amp;lt;groupId&amp;gt;com.alipay.sofa&amp;lt;/groupId&amp;gt; &amp;lt;artifactId&amp;gt;sofa-dashboard-client&amp;lt;/artifactId&amp;gt; &amp;lt;/denpendency&amp;gt; Function display</description></item><item><title>How to contribute</title><link>/en/projects/sofa-dashboard/contribution/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/en/projects/sofa-dashboard/contribution/</guid><description>We recommend that you go to the Roadmap topic to learn about the development tasks and plans first.
Prerequisites Before contributing any code, you need to know how to use the Git tools and the GitHub website.
For the use of Git tools, refer to the official Pro Git book and get familiar with it by reading the first few chapters. For the Git collaboration process, refer to Git Workflows.</description></item><item><title>Quick start</title><link>/en/projects/sofa-dashboard/quick-start/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/en/projects/sofa-dashboard/quick-start/</guid><description>This topic helps you quickly download, install, and use SOFADashboard on your computer.
Prepare the environment sofa-dashboard-backend needs to be run in a Java environment. Make sure that it can be used normally in the following runtime environments:
JDK 1.8+: Download and Configure. Maven 3.2.5+: Download and Configure. sofa-dashboard-frontend uses the Ant Design Pro scaffold. For more information about the frontend environment, see Ant Design.
Initialize the database MySQL version: 5.</description></item><item><title>Release notes</title><link>/en/projects/sofa-dashboard/release-node/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/en/projects/sofa-dashboard/release-node/</guid><description>For more information, see https://github.com/sofastack/sofa-dashboard/releases.</description></item><item><title>Roadmap and task claim</title><link>/en/projects/sofa-dashboard/roadmap/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/en/projects/sofa-dashboard/roadmap/</guid><description>Tasks The following table lists the features that have not yet been implemented. We encourage you to claim the tasks and make a contribution.
Type Task Difficulty Claimed by and on Planned completion time Progress Related issues Document SOFADashboard Parameter Configuration Guide Simple Code Support for SOFARegistry Medium Code Support for Docker Medium Code Support for Kubernetes Medium Code Support for Apollo Medium Code Frontend optimization Medium</description></item><item><title>Service governance</title><link>/en/projects/sofa-dashboard/governance/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/en/projects/sofa-dashboard/governance/</guid><description>SOFADashboard&amp;rsquo;s service governance mainly manages SOFARPC services.
Console The service governance console mainly provides two basic functions: service name query and service information display. When you click the hyperlink of a service ID, you are redirected to the details page of the service.
Service provider details page Service consumer details page</description></item><item><title>SOFAArk control</title><link>/en/projects/sofa-dashboard/ark-console/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/en/projects/sofa-dashboard/ark-console/</guid><description>SOFAArk offers a variety of methods to support multi-application (module) consolidation and deployment, including command line-based control and API-based control. SOFAArk control is an implementation of SOFADashboard&amp;rsquo;s control over APIs. SOFAArk control is implemented by pushing commands to and parsing commands in ZooKeeper.
SOFAArk control mainly provides the following functions:
Plug-in registration: registers the ark-biz package with SOFADashboard as basic data processors. Application association: binds the ark-biz package with host applications.</description></item><item><title>SOFADashboard overview</title><link>/en/projects/sofa-dashboard/overview/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/en/projects/sofa-dashboard/overview/</guid><description>SOFADashboard is designed to implement unified management over SOFA framework components, including service governance and SOFAArk control. All technology stacks used by SOFADashboard are developed and constructed based on open-source community products, such as Ant Design Pro, SOFABoot, Spring, and MyBatis.
Currently, service governance and SOFAArk control of SOFADashboard are dependent on ZooKeeper. Therefore, you need to ensure the ZooKeeper service is available when you decide to use SOFADashboard. You also need to ensure that MySQL is available, because SOFAArk control and deployment uses MySQL for resource data storage.</description></item><item><title>Version rules</title><link>/en/projects/sofa-dashboard/version-rule/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/en/projects/sofa-dashboard/version-rule/</guid><description>Version number Major, minor, and revision version numbers are used. For example, 1.0.0.
For more information, see https://semver.org/
Major version number: All versions with the same major version number must be compatible with each other. They are not necessarily fully compatible with other major versions. However, it is best to be downward compatible. Minor version number: represents feature enhancement. The larger the version number, the more features it has. Revision version number: represents the BugFix version.</description></item></channel></rss>