<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>SOFALookout on SOFAStack</title><link>/en/projects/sofa-lookout/</link><description>Recent content in SOFALookout on SOFAStack</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>zh-CN</language><atom:link href="/en/projects/sofa-lookout/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Client built-in extension metrics</title><link>/en/projects/sofa-lookout/client-ext-metrics/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/en/projects/sofa-lookout/client-ext-metrics/</guid><description>Client built-in extension metrics The extension modules currently in effect by default are lookout-ext-jvm and lookout-ext-os (from v1.5.0).
JVM thread metric name metric tags specification jvm.threads.totalStarted &amp;mdash; jvm.threads.active &amp;mdash; jvm.threads.peak &amp;mdash; jvm.threads.daemon &amp;mdash; JVM class loading metric name metric tags specification jvm.classes.unloaded &amp;mdash; jvm.</description></item><item><title>Client configuration</title><link>/en/projects/sofa-lookout/client-configuration/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/en/projects/sofa-lookout/client-configuration/</guid><description>Client configuration example lookoutConfig.setProperty(LookoutConfig.LOOKOUT_AGENT_HOST_ADDRESS,&amp;quot;127.0.0.1&amp;quot;); Description of server configuration item Configuration item Corresponding SpringBoot configuration item Default value Description lookout.enable com.alipay.sofa.lookout.enable true Function switch, it defaults to true. If you change it to false (empty objects and empty methods), then all metrics comsume almost no memory and computing resource lookout.max.metrics.num com.alipay.sofa.lookout.max-metrics-num 5000 Maximum number limit of metrics, over which will be automatically ignored lookout.</description></item><item><title>Development guide</title><link>/en/projects/sofa-lookout/development-use-guide/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/en/projects/sofa-lookout/development-use-guide/</guid><description> Develope guide of code contribution First refer to the basic Notes for code contribution Note the test case coverage; Note the code format; Verify samples Import the sample Maven project separately; Modify the dependency version in the corresponding Pom file; Verify that samples can work correctly as well.</description></item><item><title>Overview</title><link>/en/projects/sofa-lookout/overview/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/en/projects/sofa-lookout/overview/</guid><description>Introduction SOFALookout is a lightweight and open source middleware service of Ant Financial that solves the metrics and monitoring issues of the system. The services it provides include: Event logging, collecting, processing, storing, and querying of Metrics. The open source project consists of two separate parts, the client and server side services.
Client-side service SOFALookout Client is a Java SDK that helps developers log events of metrics in project code.</description></item><item><title>Project sample</title><link>/en/projects/sofa-lookout/use-guide-samples/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/en/projects/sofa-lookout/use-guide-samples/</guid><description>Some sample projects are provided in the source project to assist in the use of the project. The readme file of the sample project has additional instructions for use, and you need to import these sample projects separately into IDE.
Client-side sample project lookout-client-samples-java  This sample project demonstrates how to use and configure the client in code form in a normal Java project.
lookout-client-samples-boot  This sample project demonstrates how to use and configure the client in a SpringBoot (or SofaBoot) project.</description></item><item><title>Quick start guide for SOFABoot project</title><link>/en/projects/sofa-lookout/quick-start-client-boot/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/en/projects/sofa-lookout/quick-start-client-boot/</guid><description>This project demonstrates how to use SOFALookout in SOFABoot and connect to the Actuator of Spring Boot. If you want to connect to Prometheus or other Registry, see the Registry section.
Create a SpringBoot (or SofaBoot) project Create a new Spring Boot application (In case of SOFABoot project, import to SOFABoot as described in SOFABoot Documentation - Dependency Management.
Introduce Lookout&amp;rsquo;s Starter dependency Introduce the following dependency in pom.xml:</description></item><item><title>Quick start guide for common Java project</title><link>/en/projects/sofa-lookout/quick-start-client-java/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/en/projects/sofa-lookout/quick-start-client-java/</guid><description>Quick start for client Common Java Project Add the Maven dependency of the client to the application:
&amp;lt;dependency&amp;gt; &amp;lt;groupId&amp;gt;com.alipay.sofa.lookout&amp;lt;/groupId&amp;gt; &amp;lt;artifactId&amp;gt;lookout-client&amp;lt;/artifactId&amp;gt; &amp;lt;version&amp;gt;${lookout.client.version}&amp;lt;/version&amp;gt; &amp;lt;/dependency&amp;gt; Lookout-client relies on the lookout-reg-server module by default (supports reporting metrics data to the lookout server). If you want to use a different type of registry (such as lookout-reg-prometheus), then add the corresponding dependency.
Before starting to use the SOFALookout Client, you must firstly build a global client instance (com.</description></item><item><title>SOFARPC Metrics</title><link>/en/projects/sofa-lookout/sofarpc-metrics/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/en/projects/sofa-lookout/sofarpc-metrics/</guid><description>SOFARPC Metrics SOFARPC currently measures two metrics.
Server thread pool metric name metric tags specification rpc.bolt.threadpool.config bolt thread pool configuration Mainly includes thread pool configuration information for RPC server rpc.bolt.threadpool.active.count Running thread of the current thread pool rpc.bolt.threadpool.idle.count Idle thread of the current thread pool rpc.bolt.threadpool.queue.size Tasks in the queue of the current thread pool Client call information metric name metric tags specification rpc.</description></item><item><title>Use API</title><link>/en/projects/sofa-lookout/use-guide-api/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/en/projects/sofa-lookout/use-guide-api/</guid><description>Use client API In the design of SOFALookout client, API is decoupled from the implementation. If you need to log the events based on the SOFALookout API, you only need to add the lookout-api Maven dependency to the pom.xml file in your application/project. If the dependencies (such as client dependencies or SOFABoot (Spring Boot) Starter) do not exist, the API package uses NoopRegistry automatically, to replace all the locations of which the events are logged.</description></item><item><title>Use Registry</title><link>/en/projects/sofa-lookout/use-guide-registry/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/en/projects/sofa-lookout/use-guide-registry/</guid><description>Use Registry Different Registry integrations provide different ways to access Metrics.
1. LookoutRegistry Provides the ability to count metrics by a time window. It is divided into two modes: “active” and “passive”. The passive mode is off currently.
(1) Active mode
 You can specify the IP address of the remote agent through [Client Configuration], that is, check when start reporting, and regularly report data.
(2) Passive mode
 This mode can be activated through [Client Configuration], and HTTP service is provided on port 19399.</description></item></channel></rss>