<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>hmily on dromara(Open source organization)</title><link>/tags/hmily/</link><description>Recent content in hmily on dromara(Open source organization)</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>zh-CN</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 28 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/tags/hmily/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>One year later, the dromara team released version 2.1.1 of the new architecture Hmily distributed transaction framework</title><link>/community/hmily-2.1.1/</link><pubDate>Mon, 28 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/community/hmily-2.1.1/</guid><description>Thank you guys for your support all the way, and keep everyone waiting. In this version, our team refactored the entire project, reasonably divided functional modules, added configuration centers, adjusted the underlying storage structure, solved difficult bugs, and supported other new features, and absorbed more outstanding open source community members to join in. Architecture Features High availability·:</description></item><item><title>Hmily distributed transaction restart monthly report</title><link>/community/hmily-restart/</link><pubDate>Tue, 08 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/community/hmily-restart/</guid><description>Hmily is a flexible distributed transaction architecture with high performance, high avalibility and ease to use. At present, it provides support for Dubbo, Spring-Cloud, Motan, GRPC and other RPC frameworks. In terms of ease of use, it provides zero-intrusive rapid integration of Spring-Boot and Spring-Namespace, with the goal of building a distributed transaction solution of financial level. Adjust Hmily architecture with more reasonable module partition Architecture: Architecture adjustment: Pull out</description></item><item><title>Hmily released 2.0.2-Release</title><link>/community/hmily-2.0.2/</link><pubDate>Fri, 05 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/community/hmily-2.0.2/</guid><description>Hmily released 2.0.2-Release Resolved the issue of SpringCloud using Hystrix to configure thread pool. New issue with SpringCloud embedded transaction calls.
Added Hmily load balancing strategy.
Other bug fixes and code optimizations.
Remove unnecessary third-party JAR packages.
Introduction of zero intrusion mode.
Hmily&amp;rsquo;s support for the popular RPC framework and Spring. Dubbo 2.7.0 for all versions below. SpringCloud Dalston and above, including support for Finchley and Greenwich</description></item><item><title>Hmily: Easy Handle Highly Concurrent Distributed Transactions</title><link>/blog/hmily_current/</link><pubDate>Wed, 14 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/blog/hmily_current/</guid><description>Hmily高并发事务处理 开始先打个小小的广告 Hmily在参开源中国年度受欢迎投票 https://www.oschina.net/project/top_cn_2018?origin=zhzd 点击链接，搜索Hmily帮忙投下票,在第11横排第二个，感</description></item><item><title>Hmily: High-Performance Asynchronous Distributed Transaction TCC Framework</title><link>/blog/hmily_introuduction/</link><pubDate>Tue, 25 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/blog/hmily_introuduction/</guid><description>Hmily框架特性[https://github.com/yu199195/hmily] 无缝集成Spring,Spring boot start。 无缝</description></item></channel></rss>